{
    "id": "962a5730ee5440a583d5c3e340a942b6",
    "title": "Gap Filling Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "You must be ashamed …………………………",
            "description": "Ashamed is used with of. Also when both the subject and the object refer to the same person, we use the reflexive pronoun.",
            "answers": [
                "with yourself",
                "of you",
                "of yourself"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4d68242e6a1b4efbb14a637902795f95"
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was at university, I ……………………….. play tennis every evening.",
            "description": "We use used to to talk about past habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "was used to",
                "use to",
                "used to"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d63a00feeda34ee2985c5bf14aca7b12"
        },
        {
            "question": "She was so frightened ……………………….. she could not even move.",
            "description": "The conjunction so...that... expresses cause and effect. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "for",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "09ad6db8bb9145eeb994dab5d66cbe83"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………….. had she finished one project before she started working on the next.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Hardly",
                "As soon as",
                "No sooner"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7d7c8abfdc1b4883b73518d4ab51f287"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………… he was suffering from some health problems, the doctor advised him to take a break.",
            "description": "As gives the reason for something. ",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Though",
                "For"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3b8dc44c23864bffb52bcd56d034a0e0"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the watch ………………………. he bought for me.",
            "description": "Either that or which can refer to things in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9ab6dc35d78b452c84b6e029af51a752"
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me …………………….. I had seen his purse.",
            "description": "Either if or whether can be used to introduce an yes/no question.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "dca36c67265c446f89c851fd93fc7d57"
        },
        {
            "question": "Hindi as well as Marathi …………………….. spoken in Mumbai.",
            "description": "When we connect two singular subjects with as well as, the verb is singular. ",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is",
                "am"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3209df6dd7644ff3bf0795c188e2101b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have been living in Kerala …………………………. 5 years.",
            "description": "Use for to indicate duration. ",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "since",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8d905a8681c343eab5805448d66f2f11"
        },
        {
            "question": "I didn’t go ………………………… I hadn’t been invited.",
            "description": "Because gives the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "so",
                "because of"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a38ffbfcd74e47c5901748c3f2718e74"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. fast, the cops caught the thief.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Ran",
                "Running",
                "Having run"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "70447f6eede94e19aff18dc1f5daa493"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had invited her, she ....................................",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will come",
                "would come",
                "would have come"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "dca8dab449224e5e9256d720ca6f5d58"
        }
    ]
}